<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The effect of the Viscount Montagues bill exhibited in Parliament</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1621</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 12 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A00288</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 10406.6</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S3350</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">33143355</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 33143355</idno>
            <idno type="VID">28409</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A00288)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 28409)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1885:42)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The effect of the Viscount Montagues bill exhibited in Parliament</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1621]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Printed in two columns. The right column has: The seuerall Answers to the said points.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Society of Antiquaries.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England and Wales. --  Court of Chancery --  Cases.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  London (England) --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2007-08</date>
            <label>Aptara</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="treatise">
            <pb facs="tcp:28409:1"/>
            <div type="part">
               <head>The effect of the Viſcount Montagues bill
exhibited in Parliament.</head>
               <p>THe Viſcount on the behalfe of himſelfe and his daughters complain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth,
ſhewing that whereas in April 1611. hee conveyed diuerſe lands
to Sir <hi>Robert Dormer,</hi> ſince Lord <hi>Dormer,</hi> Sir <hi>Iohn Dormer</hi> Knight, and <hi>Fran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cis
Englefield</hi> then Eſquire, now Barronet, vpon truſt for the paiment of his
debts being neare 8000 <abbr>l</abbr>, &amp; for raiſing of a ſumme not exceeding 20000 <abbr>l</abbr>
for the mariage portions of his daughters, the remaine to be reaſſured on
the next heire male of his houſe.</p>
               <p>And whereas likewiſe he the ſaid Viſcount did convey vnto the ſaid per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons
the Mannor of <hi>Wanbarow</hi> and divers houſes in <hi>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Mary Oueries</hi> for the
raiſing of 6000 <abbr>l</abbr> more owing by him to his Maieſtie, which debt of 6000 <abbr>l</abbr>
was ſatisfied by the ſale of <hi>Wanborow</hi> onely, and for the profits of the lands
truſted, Sir <hi>Francis Englefield</hi> did take the ſame, and by foure yeares profits
thereof and the ſale of ſome part hath raiſed great ſummes.</p>
               <p>And whereas he the ſaid Viſcount by his deed dated the 25 of Iune 1613.
did aſſigne as parcel of the ſaid 20000 <abbr>l</abbr> the ſumme of 10000 <abbr>l</abbr> to his daugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter
<hi>Mary</hi> now the Ladie <hi>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Iohn,</hi> to <hi>Katherine</hi> 4000 <abbr>l</abbr>, to <hi>Mary</hi> now wife to
<hi>Robert Peter</hi> Eſquire the ſumme of 2000 <abbr>l</abbr>, of which deed the Feoffees ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uing
notice did not make paiment accordingly; neither are his the ſaid Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>counts
debts by them paid, but the Vicount inforced to pay part thereof
himſelfe; whereupon a bill was exhibited in Chancerie by the Lord <hi>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Iohn</hi>
and his Ladie for this mariage portion of 10000 <abbr>l</abbr>, which afterward was de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creed
to be paid with damages after 6 <abbr>l</abbr> for the 100 <abbr>l</abbr>.</p>
               <p>And whereas there was in the ſaid aſſurances divers errors, the ſaid Viſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count
therefore exhibited his bill in Chancery againſt his three Feoffees a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid,
deſiring that he might name new Feoffees to whom the eſtate of
theſe lands might be conveyed; for which purpoſe Sir <hi>George Moore,</hi> Sir
<hi>Iohn Walter</hi> and M. <hi>Thomas Spencer</hi> were by him nominated, who he deſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reth
may hold the ſame to the aforeſaid vſes, vpon which bill it was the 23
of Iune 1618 decreed, that Sir <hi>Francis Englefield</hi> and Sir <hi>Iohn Dormer</hi> ſhould
conuey the ſaid lands to the aforeſaid new Feoffees for the raiſing of mony
to ſatisfie the Ladie <hi>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Iohn</hi> and to diſcharge the reſidue of the truſt, by
which decree Sir <hi>Francis Englefield</hi> is inioyned to make his account, and to
pay all moneys due on the ſame to the Viſcount <hi>Montague</hi> with damages.</p>
               <p>In obedience of which decree, Sir <hi>Iohn Dormer</hi> hath conueyed his inte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſt
in the lands truſted to the ſaid new Feoffees, but Sir <hi>Francis Englefield</hi>
denieth vpon pretence that neither the Vicounts requeſt nor the Decree
of the Court can ſecure him.</p>
               <p>For that the performance of this truſt doth much concerne the Viſcounts
eſtate and his children, he deſireth to haue it enacted that Sir <hi>George Moore,</hi>
Sir <hi>Iohn Walter</hi> and M. <hi>Thomas Spencer</hi> ſhall haue to them and their heires
ſuch of the lands truſted as are yet vnſold, together with the houſes in <hi>S.
Marie Oueries,</hi> vpon truſt and confidence that they ſhal by the ſale of the
lands vnſold, or any part thereof, leuie the remain of the Ladie <hi>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Iohns</hi> por<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion
vnpaid, with the damages awarded, and the mariage portions of his
other daughters vnſatisfied, and the 1000 <abbr>l</abbr> parcell of the ſaid 10000 <abbr>l</abbr> pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able
to the Marques.</p>
               <p>It is further enacted in reſpect of the Lord <hi>Dormer</hi> deceaſed and Sir <hi>Iohn
Dormer</hi> haue not receiued any rents or profits, nor intermedled with the
truſt that they ſhall be diſcharged from the ſame; and that Sir <hi>Francis Engle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>field</hi>
paying to the Viſcount the moneys by him raiſed by ſale or main pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fits
of the ſaid lands and now in his hands, ſhall likewiſe be diſcharged of
the ſaid truſts. And if Sir <hi>Francis Englefield</hi> doe not before Whitſontide
next following make a iuſt and perfect account and pay the arrerages with
damages, that then the Viſcount may haue his action of account, and this
act to be a ſufficient ground of this action.</p>
               <p>And be it further enacted that all bonds entred into by the ſaid Viſcount
vnto Sir <hi>Robert Dormer,</hi> Sir <hi>Iohn Dormer</hi> and Sir <hi>Francis Englefield,</hi> or any
of them concerning the ſaid lands and truſt, ſhall be vtterly void.</p>
               <p>And be it further enacted, when the ſaid debts, portions, and damages
ſhall be paide, that then the lands vnſold ſhall be aſſured on <hi>Francis Browne</hi>
Eſquire, eldeſt ſonne of the ſaid Viſcount, and the heires males of his body:
and if he die without iſſue male, then to the Viſcount for life, and after to
the heires males of his body, and for want of ſuch iſſue, then to his next
heire male in blood, and to ſuch further vſes as are expreſſed in the booke
of truſt: and the ouerplus of money ariſing by the profits or ſaile, ſhall be
to the Viſcount and his heires.</p>
               <p>And it is further enacted, that the 1000 <abbr>l</abbr>. payable to the Marques of
<hi>Winton.</hi> parcel of the 10000 <abbr>l</abbr> mariage portion, being before the <hi>Annuntiatio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
                  </hi>
1622 diſcharged by Sir <hi>George Moore,</hi> Sir <hi>Iohn Walter,</hi> &amp; M. <hi>Thomas Spencer,</hi>
the Lord Marquiſſes lands ſhal be diſcharged of the Ladie <hi>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Iohns</hi> ioynture
and dowrie, and that the Lord <hi>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Iohns</hi> and his heires ſhall be acquitted and
diſcharged from the Lady <hi>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Iohn</hi> debts, charges &amp; maintenance; and after
paiment made to the Marquis of the 1000 <abbr>l</abbr> aforeſaid, all leaſes and aſſuran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces
made by the Vicount vnto Sir <hi>Rich. Weſton,</hi> Sir <hi>Rich. Farmer</hi> and Sir <hi>Ant.
Maynie</hi> for the paiment of the ſaid 10000 <abbr>l</abbr> portion to the Marquis, ſhall be
voide.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>The ſeuerall Anſwers to the
ſaid points.</head>
               <p>BY the truſt as the ſame is laid downe in the Viſcounts bill, it appeareth
that the perſons truſted are Feoffees to the vſe of ſuch next heire male
of the Viſcounts houſe as firſt after his death ſhall accompliſh the age of 21
yeares, and not to the vſe of the Viſcount, who by his deed vnder his hand
and ſeale hath wholy depriued himſelfe of all power to reuoke or alter the
ſame if he had any.</p>
               <p>The houſes in <hi>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Marie Oueries</hi> are no part of the lands ſubiect to this
truſt, yet by a <hi>Tacite truſt</hi> to be aſſured on the next heire male of the Viſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>counts
houſe, as by the Feoffees anſwer made vpon oath to the Viſcounts
bill is ſet forth.</p>
               <p>The firſt Feoffees of this truſt haue by the ſame truſt ten yeares time to
pay the Viſcounts debts, and 20 yeares to raiſe 20000 <abbr>l</abbr> payable in mariage
portions for the Viſcounts daughters, moſt of which debts and <hi>Katherines</hi>
4000 <abbr>l</abbr> mariage portion they paid with the foure yeares profits while they
held the lands, ſince which time the Viſcount himſelf and his new Feoffees
haue by the power of the Court of Chancery taken the ſame from them,
and are now in full poſſeſſion thereof, &amp; haue thereby raiſed neare 16000 <abbr>l</abbr>,
which contrary to diuers orders made in Chancery they paid not to the La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>die
<hi>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Iohn</hi> nor towards the performance of the truſt, but convert the ſame
to their owne vſe; the non paiment therefore of the Lady <hi>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Iohns</hi> 10000 <abbr>l</abbr>
not through the firſt Feoffees default but the Vicounts; no cauſe of this the
Ladie <hi>St Iohns</hi> ſuite, which ſhe fraudulently exhibited in the Lord <hi>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Iohn</hi>
her husbands name, without his priuitie, and he therefore hath diſclaimed
the ſame, as appeareth vpon record.</p>
               <p>There are no errors in theſe aſſurances, no cauſe therefore of this the Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>counts
bill which he exhibited vnder pretence only to change the Feoffees
of this truſt, but with intent vtterly to deſtroy the ſame. This Decree which
is the ground of this bill in Parliament, was by the Vicount procured by
bribes, and theſe bribes confeſſed in Parliament.</p>
               <p>By the truſt this account is not to be made to the Vicount but to the
next heire male of his houſe, yet hath Sir <hi>Francis Englefield</hi> alwaies proffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red
the ſame, and to pay the arrerages if any be to the new Feoffees, ſo he
may be ſecured from the heire male of the Viſcounts houſe, to whom by
the truſt the ſame is payable.</p>
               <p>The Viſcounts requeſt nor a decree in Chancery can ſecure Sir <hi>Francis
Englefield</hi> againſt ſuch next heire male of the Viſcounts houſe, who being
an infant or a perſon vnknowne, cannot be made partie to any bill, and
therefore not to be bound by any Decree.</p>
               <p>The Vicount by this his bill pretendeth the performance of this truſt, yet
doth he vtterly deſtroy the ſame by aſſigning the houſes in <hi>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Mary Oueries</hi>
(which are no part of the lands truſted) for y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> paiment of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> La. <hi>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Iohns</hi> portio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>.</p>
               <p>It is willingly granted y<hi rend="sup">t</hi> theſe new Feoffees ſhall be inveſted in the lands
truſted, ſo as the ſame be from Iuly 1617. euer ſince which time they haue
quietly held the lands without any interruption of the firſt Feoffees.</p>
               <p>The truſt will allow no damages to be paid, the ſumme of 10000 <abbr>l</abbr> for a
mariage portion &amp; not otherwiſe being only due, and the Marquis hauing
the intereſt of this mariage portio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> at the time when this bill was exhibited,
this Lady could receiue no damage, &amp; therfore could expect no reco<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>pence.</p>
               <p>The Lord <hi>Dormer,</hi> and Sir <hi>Iohn Dormer</hi> haue intermedled in this truſt as
farre as Sir <hi>Francis Englefield</hi> hath, onely Sir <hi>Francis Englefield</hi> confeſſeth to
haue receiued and disburſed all the moneys by reaſon of this truſt, and
proffereth his account for the ſame, and for this purpoſe deſireth that in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>different
Auditors may be appointed.</p>
               <p>It is meant by this, to make voide the ſtatute of 20000 <abbr>l</abbr>, acknowledged
by the Vicount to the firſt Feoffees, for the performance of his couenants
contained in the ſaid booke of truſt: this therefore being parcell of the
aſſurances, may not without deſtroying the truſt be made voide.</p>
               <p>The ſurpluſage of the lands vnſold, are by the truſt appointed to raiſe
portions for all the Vicounts yonger ſonnes, and for want of yonger ſonnes
to be reaſſured on ſuch next heire male of the Viſcounts houſe as firſt after
his death ſhall accompliſh 21 yeares, the transferring therfore of theſe lands
on the Vicounts ſon <hi>Francis Browne</hi> in the Viſcounts life, is contrary to the
direction of the ſaid truſt: the ouerplus of mony likewiſe is by the truſt ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed
to the ſaid next heire male of the Vicounts houſe; the Vicount
therefore by requiring the paiment of this ouerplus to himſelfe, doth vt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terly
deſtroy this truſt.</p>
               <p>It appeareth by Articles before the Lady <hi>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Iohns</hi> mariage, and by a deed
executed vnder the hands and ſeales of the Vicount, the Lord <hi>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Iohn</hi> and
his Ladie made after mariage, that the Marquis of <hi>Winton,</hi> was to receiue the
whole 10000 <abbr>l</abbr> mariage portion; but it appeareth not how the Lord Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quis
ſhould haue onely 1000 <abbr>l</abbr> thereof, and to be diſcharged of the Ladie
<hi>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Iohns</hi> ioynture.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
